#### ADAM ROBOTTOM

Mobile: 07581323852 EMAIL: adamrobottom@yahoo.co.uk

### **Profile**

A dependable and highly motivated individual with over ten years experience as a Corporal in the Royal Marines, is versatile and adaptable to any environment, can apply discretion and integrity at the highest level. A proven track record of success in challenging environments, under duress and against tight timelines. Effective communicator with a decisive and measured leadership style, with exceptional personal discipline and professional bearing.

## **Key Skills**

- Effective decision maker and problem solver in challenging locations in arduous situations.
- Dedicated to team building, camaraderie and Continuous Personal Development (CPD).
- Exemplary attention to detail, along with superior verbal and written reporting skills.
- Team player, with the ability to inspire and motivate under challenging circumstances.
- Excellent observation skills that have been tried and tested at the highest level.

### **Professional Qualifications**

- 2014 Close Protection Course level 3 (BTEC)
- 2014 Level 2 Intermediate FPOSi (BTEC)
- 2014 Level 3 Education and Training
- 2014 Level 3 Advance driving (BTEC)
- 2014 Handgun and Rifle competency

- 2014 DBS clean
- 2014 SIA licence
- 2011 Advance search team course
- 2011 Diploma in Team Leading
- 2004 Drivers licence clean (B,BE,B1,C,CE,C1,C1E,f,k,p)

# Career History

## Maritime Security Operator

2014-Present

A professional maritime security operator with an important level of security awareness and response training. To provide the client robust and effective security assurance and appropriate responses to all maritime threats and incidents.

- Provided security to a variety of commercial vessels, transiting through different locations and territories. Working with assigned Rules of Engagement within the international environment.
- Have successfully integrated with all crew members, of different nationalities and cultures in order to provide an excellent working environment while the security team is onboard.

## **Royal Marines Section Commander/Acting Sergeant**

2011-2014

An accountable commander for eight junior marines in challenging environments, conducting a variety of mission and tasks, while working with foreign counter parts in order to mentor and develop the team professionally.

- Provided Ships Protection for a large sea going Ship, within this appointment held the rank of acting sergeant. Responsible for a team of 15 junior marines deployed to various countries in order to maintain the ships security.
- Deployed on large operational exercise in September 2013, this was a 42 Commando Unit exercise. Conducted training in several diverse countries including Albania, Turkey, Djibouti and Oman. Training and developing the local forces, in order to enhance professional performance.

Adam Robottom Page 1

- Conducted an Exercise in Jordan. Working with America Marines in order to develop both our own and their skills.
- 2012 London Olympics. Managed a team of up to 30 marines covering 5 different control points, in order to maintain security throughout the games, which proved highly successful.
- April 2011 deployed to Afghanistan for a 6 month deployment commanding a section of men, while
  working with the Afghan Nation Army in order to provide a sustainable security force while
  conducting missions in very challenging and arduous terrain, utilised high level observation skill for
  large periods in order to maintain the security of the patrol against a determined enemy. All of
  which was conducted from a forward operating base in the heart of Helmand province.

## 2 I/C of Fire Support Group

2008-2010

A Section 2 I/C in charge of a fire team of men, used a variety of diverse vehicles and operated in different types of terrain, while working with many different nations and conducting operations on a large scale. Navigated a company of men through Helmand province using a series of rendezvous points into hostile areas.

- Successfully completed Junior Command Course. Consisted of 12 weeks of training, conducted various command training in order to be promoted to corporal. Carried out on numerous occasions written reporting skills and applied verbal command whilst being put under large amount of pressure.
- October 2008- April 2009 deployed to Afghanistan. The role encompassed that of a vehicle commander in a highly kinetic environment. In command of all fire support from my vehicle weapons platform and also lead the company on large scale roads using highest level of observation skills and communication with over 30 vehicles in order to complete all necessary missions.
- June 2008 successful completed a Heavy Weapon command course. Taught how to facilitate numerous weapon systems and also conducted tactical training on how to deploy each section.

### **Heavy Weapons Specialist**

2004-2008

Royal Marine heavy weapons specialist operated a range of weapons, whilst carried out operations against a resilient enemy. Trained and successfully completed operations in a variety of environments, which enabled the development of observation skills and personal discipline to an extremely high level.

- January 2008 deployed to Norway to completed cold weather training course lasting over 2 months in sub zero temperatures.
- October 2006-April 2007 deployed to Afghanistan as a heavy weapons specialist operating the Javelin Missile, Heavy Machine Gun and Grenade Machine Gun.
- 2004 passed out of training as an original and conducted a Heavy Weapons course at Lympstone Exeter.

### **Honours and Awards**

- 2011 Operation Herrick 14 (Afghanistan)
- Diamond Jubilee Medal
- 2009 Operation Herrick 9 (Afghanistan)
- 2007 Operation Herrick 5 (Afghanistan)
- NATO ISAF Medals for all three tours

### **Activities and Interests**

- Scuba Divining (Padi Advanced)
- Sky Diving (Advanced Free Fall)
- Cycling
- Running
- Current Affairs

Adam Robottom Page 2